Arizona Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, 1909-1998
University of Arizona Library Special Collections
Arizona Association of Family and Consumer Sciences records, 1909-1998
MS 335
Arizona Association of Family and Consumer Sciences
Historical material includes scrapbooks, photographs, letters, speeches, philosophy and objectives, and materials from the 50th and 75th American Home Economics Association anniversary celebrations. Organizational materials includes the constitution, bylaws, handbooks, membership and officer rosters, and list of properties owned. Business and meeting information includes minutes from meetings of the state and sectional divisions, reports from the various divisions and officers, and corporate related materials such as incorporation, tax status and insurance records.
6.25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
State affiliate of the American Association of Family Consumer Sciences. The name was changed from Arizona Home Economics Association in 1994.
Organization
This collection is organized into six series:
Series I: Historical Materials, 1920-1992
Series II: Organization, 1920-1998
Series III: Meetings, 1939-1998
Series IV: Business, 1922-1998
Series V: Reports, 1936-1998
Series VI: Publications, 1909-1998
Scope and Content Note
Historical material includes scrapbooks, photographs, letters, speeches, philosophy and objectives, and materials from the 50th and 75th American Home Economics Association anniversary celebrations. Organizational materials includes the constitution, bylaws, handbooks, membership and officer rosters, and list of properties owned. Business and meeting information includes minutes from meetings of the state and sectional divisions, reports from the various divisions and officers, and corporate related materials such as incorporation, tax status and insurance records.
Access Terms
Home economics -- Societies, etc.
Home economics -- Arizona
Professional Associations -- Arizona
Scrapbooks
Minutes
Correspondence
Container List
- Series I: Historical Material, 1920-1992
  - Articles. (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks. 1920-1985 (Box 1)
    Five scrapbooks, to date, containing newspaper articles, photographs and awards.
  - Materials for scrapbooks. 1955-1992 (Box 1)
    Includes speeches, newspaper articles and photographs.
  - Anniversary Celebrations. (Box 1)
    Information relating to the association's 50th anniversary in 1959 and their 75th anniversary in 1984.
  - Letters, etc. 1944-1973 (Box 1)
  - Philosophy and Objectives. (Box 1)
  - Recognitions. (Box 1)
  - Dedications. (Box 1)
  - Interpretations of profession for laymen. (Box 1)
  - Logos. (Box 1)
  - Arizona fact sheets. (Box 1)
  - Other. (Box 1)
- Series II: Organization, 1920-1998
  - Constitution and Bylaws. (Box 1)
  - Handbooks. (Box 1)
  - Rosters. 1920-1998 (Box 1)
    Includes membership directories, executive board lists and membership information for sectional organizations.
  - List of properties owned. (Box 1)
- Series III: Meetings, 1939-1998
  - State meetings. 1939-1998 (Box 2)
    Planning, Programs, Exhibits, Other
  - Sectional meetings. 1945-1983 (Box 2)
    Northern, Central, Southern, Eastern and other Sectionals.
- Series IV: Business, 1922-1998
  - Minutes of AZAFCS (AZHEA). 1922-1989 (Box 2)
  - Minutes of AZAFCS (AZHEA) Executive Board (also known as AZHEA Executive Committee and Council). 1946-1998 (Box 2)
  - Minutes of Sectional Organizations. (Box 2)
  - Ceremonies, Installation and Initiation. (Box 2)
  - Special gifts. (Box 2)
  - Incorporation. (Box 2)
  - Tax exempt status. (Box 2)
  - Insurance. (Box 2)
- Series V: Reports, 1936-1998
  - AZAFCS (AZHEA) Officers' reports. 1936-1990 (Box 3)
    Includes reports from the President, Vice President-Finance, Vice President-Programs, Vice President-Professional Development, Vice President-Internal Affairs and the Vice President-Public Affairs.
  - Committee reports. (Box 4)
    Includes reports from both standing and special committees.
  - Section reports. (Box 4)
    Includes reports from division sections and professional sections.
  - Individual Appointments. (Box 5)
  - Regional Chairmen reports. (Box 5)
    Includes reports from the chairmen of the sectional organizations.
  - AZAFCS (AZHEA) Representatives to other groups. (Box 5)
    Other organizations include the Arizona Nutrition Council, honorary fraternities and AZVA/VHE.
- Series VI: Publications, 1909-1998
  - Home Economics Bookshelf. (Box 5)
  - Newsletters. 1938-1998 (Box 5)
  - National publications. 1909-1954 (Box 5)
    Includes publications from the AHEA, SAGA, AHEA (1949) and the Eastern Massachusetts Home Economics Association: the First Forty-three Years, (1909-1952, 1954).
  - State publications. (Box 5)
  - Books by members. (Box 5)